A Guide to the Evelyn Millicent Horton Collection, 1932-1973
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
Evelyn Millicent Horton Collection, 1932-1973
The Edgar Cayce Foundation, Virginia Beach, Virginia
Coll. 34
0.4 Linear Feet 1 box.
Horton, Evelyn Millicent
Arrangement
Collection arranged alphabetically by material type.
Biographical / Historical
Evelyn Millicent Horton was born on March 12, 1899 in New York City to James Madison Horton and Ida Lewis Collier Horton. She worked as a lab statistician, a war industry worker during the First World War, and conducted research at the American Psychical Institute with Dr. Hereward Carrington.
Horton received readings from Edgar Cayce and remained friends with the Cayce family. She worked briefly at the Association for Research and Enlightenment, where she wrote a pamphlet on Egypt-related readings and edited the A.R.E. Bulletin.
She died on January 30, 1984 in Pinellas, Florida at the age of 84.
Custodial History
Collection originally part of the A.R.E. New York Center record series (coll. 14).
Scope and Contents
This collection includes Evelyn Millicent Horton's correspondence and personal collection of publications related to her work with the American Psychical Institute and the Association for Research and Enlightenment.
- Box 1
  - A.R.E. publications, 1937-1967; Folder 1:1
  - article [A Pack of Cards - A Prayer Book - And A Bible], undated; Folder 1:2
  - articles [J. Francis Small], 1936-1939; Folder 1:3
  - article [Padre Pio The Stigmatist], undated; Folder 1:4
  - article [The Book of Revelation] Nesta Crane; Dorothy Herzog, 1938; Folder 1:5
  - article [The Silence], undated; Folder 1:6
  - Book Notes [Hugh Lynn Cayce], 1954-1957; Folder 1:7
  - bulletin [American Psychical Institute] Hereward Carrington; Nandor Fodor, 1935; Folder 1:8
  - Congress booklets, 1938-1946; Folder 1:9
  - correspondence, 1945-1946; Folder 1:10
  - diagrams [Great Pyramid at Giza] J. Francis Small, undated; Folder 1:11
  - essay [His Own Country] Gladys Davis, 1949; Folder 1:12
  - lecture [excerpts from Gnani Yoga] Yogi Ramachavaka, undated; Folder 1:13
  - lecture [Mantras] Swami Radha; Swami Turiyananda, undated; Folder 1:14
  - lecture [Ouspensky and Cayce] Dion M. GyllenHammar, 1969; Folder 1:15
  - lecture [Talk on Health], 1969; Folder 1:16
  - lecture [The Subconscious Mind in Aetheronics] M.A. Kretschmer, 1932; Folder 1:17
  - newsclippings, 1942-1969; Folder 1:18
  - questionnaire [Emmet Fox], undated; Folder 1:19
  - radio transcript [The Voice of Unity] Eric Butterworth, 1973; Folder 1:20
  - readings [J.C. Hobson], 1924; undated; Folder 1:21
  - sermon [Thou Shall Have Purpose: The Eleventh Commandment] Rabbi Joseph H. Gelberman, 1965; Folder 1:22